mono.net 2013-11-06

# Privacy Policy | mono.net

**1\. Introduction**

This privacy policy addresses how mono solutions ApS (“mono.net” or “mono”) uses and protects the information that you provide to mono.net when you use www.mono.net and any related websites managed by or on behalf of mono.net.

mono.net takes your privacy very seriously and is committed to making sure your privacy is protected. Any personally identifiable information you provide to mono.net will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

The latest version of mono.net’s privacy policy is always available on this page. We encourage you to check this page every so often to ensure you are happy with the policy.  This policy was last updated March 2013.  

**2\. Acceptance**

By using or accessing mono.net, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

**2a. Notice to visitors from outside of the European Union**

You should be aware that the European Union and other countries have not harmonized their privacy regulations.  Because mono.net and its servers are located in the European Union, mono.net has written its Privacy Policy to satisfy European Union regulations. By using mono.net, you agree to the level of privacy protection set out in our Privacy Policy.

**3\. Data that mono.net collects**

**3a. mono FREE subscriptions**

The first time you sign up at mono.net for a FREE subscription we ask for the following:

  * A site username
  * A valid email address
  * A password

After completing the form, you will be set up with a mono account and a mono FREE subscription for the site username you provided.  You will receive a welcome email describing your new mono.net account and mono site including how to get started and how to manage your account going forward.

**3b. mono Paid subscriptions**

Should you wish to upgrade your FREE subscription to any paid subscription, we will require additional information including:

  * Your full name
  * Company name
  * VAT number (if relevant)
  * Your address
  * Payment card details (note that do not hold credit card details in our database)

mono.net does not store your payment card details. Our payment gateway company (Quickpay) will, however, store the information required for your automatic billing (per mono.net’s Terms & Conditions) on their secure servers. mono.net may retain the credit card type and the last 4 digits of your credit card number to help you identify the card used in the future.

When you cancel your subscription, your contact information will be removed from our database and your billing information from our payment gateway provider.

**4\. What we do with the personal information we gather**

The information that we collect and store relating to you is primarily used to enable us to provide our services to you.

However, we may also use your information:

  * For information to improve our products and services
  * To send out notifications regarding service related issues, such as maintenance periods, billing problems, account expirations, and other items that may impact service
  * To send promotional email communications about special offers, news, product updates or other information, which we think you may find interesting - you may opt out of these email communications.
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes.

We will not provide your details to any third parties for marketing purposes, without your prior consent.

**  4a. Communications with mono.net**

We use third party service providers to help us manage and administer email communications with mono.net subscribers including support inquiries, newsletters, marketing mails, etc. Any personal information disclosed through such communications will be governed by these third party vendors’ privacy policy.

Should you contact us email or by any other method - we may hold the contact details or any additional information you provide to us on record for future reference and use.

**4b. Storage of your personal data**

Data that is provided to us is stored on our secure servers. We do not store credit card details on our servers.  Any credit card details given are stored on the secure servers of our PCI-certified payment gateway company (QuickPay).

**4c. Testimonials**

We post customer testimonials on mono.net site, which may contain personally identifiable information.  We obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting any testimonial which includes personally identifiable information (eg. the customer’s name). If you wish to request the removal of your testimonial you may contact us at info@mono.net or via your mono Account Center.

**5\. Security**

Security is taken very seriously at mono.net. All user information stored by mono.net is stored in secure databases protected via a variety of industry-standard access controls. However, no company, including mono.net, can fully eliminate security risks associated with the transmission of personal information through online transactions, and you do so at your own risk.

You are personally responsible for keeping any password we have given you, or you have chosen for any of your mono.net services, safe and confidential. 

**6\. Cookies**

 A cookie is a small file, which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Most browsers allow cookies by default. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual by recognizing preferences both user defined and location defined.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the mono.net and other websites.

Overall, cookies helps mono.net provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

**6a. mono.net cookies**

mono.net uses cookies to facilitate a personalized and uninterrupted connection to our service. We use cookies to ‘remember’ information about your preferences and keep you logged into your mono site/account during a given session. Note that if you disable cookies you may experience that some of mono.net services, features or other elements are not available or do not work, as they should.

**6b. Third-party cookies**

Traffic Log Cookies

We use third-party traffic log cookies (Google Analytics & PIWIK) to identify which pages are being accessed and how. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to customise it better for user needs. We use this information for statistical analysis purposes only.

Advertising Cookies

We partner with a third party ad network (Google) to manage our advertising on other sites.  Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out of Google remarketing by clicking [here](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to see generic ads.

Social media cookies

mono.net includes social sharing features (eg. the Facebook ‘like button’). These features may collect information such as which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on mono.net. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**8\. Links to other websites**

mono.net may contain links to other websites. We are of course not responsible for the privacy practices of other web sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site to read the privacy statements of any web site that collects personal information. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by mono.net or posted on the mono.net website.

Please note, mono.net holds no responsibility over any data or transactions, which you submit or transact through sites created and published by mono.net users or on mono.net subdomains eg. usersite.mono.net.

**9\. Controlling your personal information**

**9a. Changing Information**

All information that mono.net stores related to your account, including your contact and billing information, is accessible through your mono.net Account Center. You can use this area to update your information at any time.  In fact, we highly encourage you to keep this information up to date so that your support requests and billing processes operate smoothly.

**9b. Removing Information**

To remove your information from our system, you need to cancel any active subscriptions.  You can do this in the mono.net Account Center. Your personal information will be removed immediately, but your site username may remain reserved on our system.

**10\. Disclosing and sharing your information**

mono.net uses third-party service providers to perform some services on our behalf, including credit card processing, email services, data analysis and customer support functions. These service providers have access to personal information needed to perform such functions on our behalf.

mono.net reserves the right to share all collected information with its parent, affiliates and other related businesses.

mono.net reserves the right to publish or otherwise disclose user mono sites. This is also the case with received queries from users (eg. through the support function or via the various feedback mechanisms), either to clarify or answer a given query, or to guide and inspire other users.

We may release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; enforce or apply our Terms of Service; or protect the rights, property, or safety of mono.net, our users, or others.

Other than as set out above, you will receive notice when information about you might go to third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information.

**11\. Contact mono.net**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us by using our support ticket system via your mono Account center.

mono.net is located at:  
mono solutions ApS  
Baggensensgade 4C  
2200 København N  
Denmark

All correspondence should be sent to:

mono solutions ApS  
RE: Privacy Concern  
Baggensensgade 4C  
2200 København N  
Denmark
